Register of the Józef Frejlich Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1893-1966
  - Zwiazek Socjalistow Polskich w Stanach Zjednoczonych., See also Fischler, Wladyslaw
    - Clippings
      - 1905
        - March-April (Folder 28: 5)
        - December (Folder 28: 6)
      - 1906 (Folder 28: 7)
      - 1906-1907 (Folder 28: 8)
      - 1911-1912 (Box-folder 29: 1)
      - 1911-1915 (Folder 29: 2)
      - 1913 (Folder 29: 3)
      - 1914 (Folder 29: 4)
      - 1914-1917 (Folder 29: 5)
      - 1915 (Folder 29: 6)
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 29: 7)
      - 1916
        - February-July (Folder 29: 8)
        - March-June (Box-folder 30: 1)
        - June-August (Folder 30: 2)
      - 1916-1917 (Folder 30: 3)
      - 1918 (Folder 30: 4)
        - 1943-1945 (Folder 30: 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General,1939-1950. (Folder 30: 6)
        Includes clippings, 1961, re protests against Soviet occupation of Poland
      - Arciszewski, Tomasz, 1944-1945 (Folder 30: 7)
      - Buyno, Adam, 1947 (Folder 30: 8)
      - Goldman, Waclaw, 1955 (Folder 30: 9)
      - Polska Partia Socjalistyczna
        - General, 1942-1948 (Folder 30: 10)
        - Kot, Stanislaw, 1940-1944 (Folder 30: 11)
        - Stanczyk, Jan, 1940-1942 (Folder 30: 12)
    - Speeches - L. Gutman on international Zionism and condition of the Jews in Poland, 1945 (?) (Folder 30: 13)
- CLIPPINGS, 1940-1948 (Box 31)
  - 1940
    - General (Folder 31: 1)
    - French (Folder 31: 2)
    - German (Folder 31: 3)
  - 1941
    - English (Folder 31: 4)
    - French (Folder 31: 5-6)
    - French (Box-folder 32: 1)
    - German (Folder 32: 2-5)
    - German (Box-folder 33: 1-4)
    - German (Box-folder 34: 1-3)
      - Spanish (Folder 34: 4)
  - 1942
    - English (Folder 34: 5-6)
    - English (Box-folder 35: 1-3)
    - French (Folder 35: 4)
    - German (Folder 35: 5-8)
    - German (Box-folder 36: 1-3)
    - German and Russian (Folder 36: 4)
    - German (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
    - Polish (Folder 37: 3-5)
    - Polish (Box-folder 38: 1-5)
    - Russian (Folder 38: 6)
    - Russian (Box-folder 39: 1-6)
  - 1943 (Box 40)
    - English (Folder 40: 1-7)
    - English (Box-folder 41: 1-9)
    - English (Box-folder 42: 1-6)
    - German (Folder 42: 7-11)
    - Polish (Box-folder 43: 1-6)
    - Polish (Box-folder 44: 1-7)
    - Polish (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Russian (Folder 45: 2-6)
    - Russian (Box-folder 46: 1-8)
  - 1944 (Box 47)
    - English (Folder 47: 1-7)
    - English (Box-folder 48: 1-6)
    - English (Box-folder 49: 1-4)
    - German (Folder 49: 5-8)
    - Polish (Box-folder 50: 1-7)
    - Russian (Folder 51: 1-8)
  - 1945 (Box 52)
    - English (Folder 52: 1-6)
    - English (Box-folder 53: 1-6)
    - English (Box-folder 54: 1-2)
    - German (Folder 54: 3-9)
    - Polish (Folder 54: 10-11)
    - Polish (Box-folder 55: 1-5)
    - Russian (Folder 55: 6-8)
    - Russian (Box-folder 56: 1-5)
    - Russian (Box-folder 57: 1-6)
  - 1946 (Box 58)
    - English (Folder 58: 1-5)
    - French (Box-folder 59: 1-4)
    - German (Folder 59: 5-7)
    - German (Box-folder 60: 1-2)
    - Polish (Folder 60: 3-4)
    - Russian (Folder 60: 5-8)
    - Russian (Box-folder 61: 1-5)
  - 1947 (Box 62)
    - English (Folder 62: 1-2)
    - French (Folder 62: 3-5)
    - French (Box-folder 63: 1-5)
    - French (Box-folder 64: 1)
    - German (Folder 64: 2)
    - Russian (Folder 64: 3-5)
  - 1948
    - English (Folder 64: 6)
    - French (Folder 64: 7)
    - French (Box-folder 65: 1-4)
    - German (Folder 65: 5)
    - Polish (Folder 65: 6)
    - Russian (Folder 65: 7)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1920-1961 (Box 66)
  - Bulletins.
    Includes some newspapers and clippings
    - General (Folder 66: 1)
    - Austrian Republic, 1947-1948 (Folder 66: 2)
    - Berliner Boersen Zeitung, 1944 (Folder 66: 3)
    - Biuletyn Informacje i Materialy dla Narodowcow, 1946-1947 (Folder 66: 4)
    - Biuletyn Informacyjny A.K., 1954 (Folder 66: 5)
    - Biuletyn Informacyjny Instytutu Badania Zagadnien Krajowych, 1952 (Folder 66: 6)
    - Biuletyn Informacyjny Niezaleznego Ruchu Spolecznego, 1957 (Folder 66: 7)
    - Biuletyn Informacyjny Polskiego Stronnictwa Ludowego, 1952 (Folder 66: 8)
    - Biuletyn Krajowy, 1953 (Folder 66: 9)
    - Biuletyn Polski: Polskie Centrum Informacyjne, 1942 (Folder 66: 10)
    - Biuletyn Prawniczy
      - 1942 (Folder 66: 11)
      - 1943 (Folder 66: 12)
      - 1944 (Box-folder 67: 1)
      - 1945 (Folder 67: 2)
      - 1946 (Folder 67: 3)
    - Biuletyn Rozglosni Kraj
      - 1955 (Folder 67: 4)
      - 1956 (Folder 67: 5)
    - Bulletin of Liberal Democratic Union of Central Eastern Europe in the United States of America, 1955-1957 (Folder 67: 6)
    - Bulletin of the International Federation of Trade Unions, 1943 (Folder 67: 7)
    - Central and Eastern European Planning Board. Documents and Reports, 1942-1943 (Folder 67: 8)
    - Central European Federalist
      - 1958 (Folder 67: 9)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 68: 1)
      - 1960 (Folder 68: 2)
      - 1961 (Folder 68: 3)
    - Christian Democratic News Service: Christian Democratic Union of Central Europe
      - 1951 (Folder 68: 4)
      - 1952 (Folder 68: 5)
      - 1953 (Folder 68: 6)
      - 1954 (Folder 68: 7)
    - Citizens for Victory: National Labor Division. Labor for Victory Press Service, 1943-1944 (Folder 68: 8)
    - Council of Free Czechoslovakia: Information Bulletin, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 69: 1)
    - Egzekutywa Zjednoczenia Narodowego: Dzial Informacji, 1955 (Folder 69: 2)
    - France Speaks
      - 1941 (Folder 69: 3)
      - 1942 (Folder 69: 4)
      - 1943 (Folder 69: 5)
    - Ghetto Speaks, The
      - 1942 (Folder 70: 1)
      - 1943 (Folder 70: 2)
      - 1944 (Folder 70: 3)
    - Glos Wolny, 1948-1953 (Folder 70: 4)
    - Highlights of Current Legislation and Activities in Mid-Europe, 1956-1959 (Folder 70: 5)
    - Informations serbes: Service de presse, n.d.1945-1946? (Folder 70: 6)
    - Jewish Labor Committee, 1943-1944 (Folder 70: 7)
    - Kauner Zeitung, 1944 (Folder 70: 8)
    - Klub Polskich Ziem Zachodnich, 1944-1945 (Folder 70: 9)
    - Labor News from Britain
      - 1943 (Folder 70: 10)
      - 1944 (Folder 70: 11)
      - 1945 (Folder 70: 12)
    - Labor Press Service, 1944 (Folder 70: 13)
    - Labor Reports (Box 71)
      - 1944 (Folder 71: 1)
      - 1945 (Folder 71: 2)
    - Listy z Hiszpanii, 1950-1951 (Folder 71: 3)
    - Ministerstwo Spraw Kongresowych: Przeglad Literatury Politycznej, 1945 (Folder 71: 4)
    - Ministerstwo Spraw Wewnetrznych Wydzial Spoleczny: Przeglad Prasy Podziemnej
      - 1942 November - 1943 January (Folder 71: 5)
      - 1943 February-May (Folder 71: 6)
      - 1944
        - February (Folder 71: 7)
        - March-April
          - Part 1 (Folder 71: 8)
          - Part 2 (Folder 71: 9)
        - May-June (Folder 71: 10)
        - May-July
          - Part 1 (Folder 71: 11)
          - Part 2 (Folder 71: 12)
    - Ministerstwo Spraw Wewnetrznych Wydzial Spoleczny: Sprawozdanie Sytuacyjne z Ziem Polskich (Box 72)
      - 1939 September - 1940 November (Folder 72: 1)
      - 1940 November - 1941 February (Folder 72: 2)
      - 1941 November - 1942 January (Folder 72: 3)
      - 1942
        - January-March (Folder 72: 4)
        - January-April
          - Part 1 (Folder 72: 5)
          - Part 2 (Folder 72: 6)
      - 1943
        - September-October (Folder 72: 7)
        - October (Folder 72: 8)
        - October-November (Folder 72: 9)
        - November (Folder 72: 10)
        - October-December (Folder 73: 1)
      - 1943 December - 1944 January (Folder 73: 2)
      - 1943 December - 1944 February (Folder 73: 3)
      - 1944 February-June (Folder 73: 4)
    - Morze, 1937 (Folder 73: 5)
    - Mysl Polska
      - 1941 (Folder 73: 6)
      - 1942 (Folder 73: 7)
      - 1943 (Folder 73: 8)
      - 1944 (Folder 73: 9)
      - 1945 (Folder 73: 10)
    - Narodowe Biuro Informacyjne, 1952-1953 (Folder 73: 11)
    - Nasza Trybuna, 1940 (Folder 73: 12)
    - National Committee for a Free Europe: Research and Publications Service: Polish Section, 1951 (Folder 73: 13)
    - New Poland, 1950 (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - News from the Nation Associates, 1944-1945 (Folder 74: 2)
    - Nowa Polska, 1944 (Folder 74: 3)
    - Office of War Information: Foreign Language Division, 1943 (Folder 74: 4)
    - Overseas News Agency
      - 1944 (Folder 74: 5)
      - 1945 (Folder 74: 6)
    - Polak w Meksyku, 1945 (Folder 74: 7)
    - Poland of Today
      - 1946 (Folder 74: 8)
      - 1948 (Folder 74: 9)
    - Polish Art and Film, 1938 (Folder 74: 10)
    - Polish Embassy Information Bureau-Chunking
      - Chinese edition
        - 1944
          - July (Folder 74: 11)
          - August (Folder 74: 12)
          - September (Folder 74: 13)
          - October (Folder 74: 14)
          - November (Folder 74: 15)
          - December (Folder 74: 16)
        - 1945
          - January (Folder 74: 17)
          - February (Folder 74: 18)
          - March (Folder 74: 19)
          - July (Folder 74: 20)
      - English edition (Box 75)
        - 1944
          - May-June (Folder 75: 1)
          - July (Folder 75: 2)
          - August (Folder 75: 3)
          - September (Folder 75: 4)
          - October (Folder 75: 5)
          - November (Folder 75: 6)
          - December (Folder 75: 7)
        - 1945
          - January (Folder 75: 8)
          - February (Folder 75: 9)
          - March (Folder 75: 10)
          - April (Folder 75: 11)
          - May (Folder 75: 12)
          - June (Folder 75: 13)
          - July (Folder 75: 14)
    - Polish Embassy Washington Press Office Press Release
      - 1951 (Folder 75: 15)
      - 1952 (Folder 75: 16)
      - 1953 (Folder 75: 17)
      - 1954 (Folder 75: 18)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 76: 1)
      - 1956 (Folder 76: 2)
      - 1957 (Folder 76: 3)
      - 1958 (Folder 76: 4)
    - Polish Facts and Figures
      - 1944 (Folder 76: 5)
      - 1945 (Folder 76: 6)
    - Polish Labor Fights, 1942-1944 (Folder 76: 7)
    - Polpress News, 1945 (Folder 77: 1)
    - Polpress Polish Press Agency Bulletin, 1945 (Folder 77: 2)
    - Polska Agencja Telegraficzna: Biuletyn.
      Includes frequent references to Auschwitz and German oppression on Polish territory
      - 1943 (Folder 77: 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 77: 4)
      - 1945 (Folder 77: 5)
      - 1946 (Folder 77: 6)
      - 1947 (Folder 77: 7)
      - 1952 (Folder 77: 8)
      - 1953 (Folder 77: 9)
      - 1956 (Folder 77: 10)
      - 1957 (Folder 77: 11)
    - Polsko-Amerykanska Rada Pracy, 1950 (Folder 77: 12)
    - Polsko-Amerykanskie Wiadomosci Robotnicze, 1951 (Folder 77: 13)
    - Przeglad Polski
      - 1946 (Folder 77: 14)
      - 1947
        - January-June (Folder 77: 15)
        - July-December (Box-folder 78: 1)
      - 1948
        - January-June (Folder 78: 2)
        - July-December (Folder 78: 3)
      - 1949 (Folder 78: 4)
    - Przeglad Zachodni, 1953 (Folder 78: 5)
    - République française
      - 1943 (Folder 78: 6)
      - 1944 (Folder 78: 7)
    - Robotnik polski, 1945 (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - Russian War Relief, 1943 (Folder 79: 2)
    - Rzeczpospolita, 1945 (Folder 79: 3)
    - Sprawa Slaska Cieszynskiego: Biuletyn, 1942-1943 (Folder 79: 4)
    - Sprawozdanie Egzekutywy Zjednoczenia Narodowego, 1957-1966 (Folder 79: 5)
    - Stowarzyszenie Polskich Kombatantow Oddzial Szwecja: Biuletyn, 1954 (Folder 79: 6)
    - Swiatowy Zwiazek Polakow z Zagranicy: Biuletyn Organizacyjny, 1943 (Folder 79: 7)
    - Swiatpol Polska Agencja Prasowa, 1943-1949 (Folder 79: 8)
    - Tygodnik Polski, 1944
      - January-June (Folder 79: 9)
      - July-December (Folder 79: 10)
    - United States: Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, 1958 (Box-folder 80: 1)
    - Voice of Freedom: Monthly Bulletin of the International Co-Ordination Council, 1941-1942 (Folder 80: 2)
    - Voice of the Unconquered: Monthly Newsletter of the Jewish Labor Committee, 1943-1945 (Folder 80: 3)
    - W Drodze
      - 1943 (Folder 80: 4)
      - 1944 (Folder 80: 5)
    - Weltwoche, 1944 (Folder 80: 6)
    - Wiadomosci Krajowe Biuletyny, 1948 (Folder 80: 7)
    - Za Wolnosc i Niepodleglosc
      - 1947 (Folder 80: 8)
      - 1948 (Folder 80: 9)
      - 1949 (Folder 80: 10)
      - 1950 (Folder 80: 11)
    - Zagadnienia Polskie (Box 81)
      - 1954 (Folder 81: 1)
      - 1955 (Folder 81: 2)
  - Cartoons published in the Polish-American daily Dziennik Zwiazkowy Zgoda, 1943-1946 (Folder 81: 3)
  - Flyers
    - General, 1941-1947 (Folder 81: 4)
    - European elections and power struggle - Communists and anti-Communists, 1945-1955
      - French (Folder 81: 5)
      - German (Folder 81: 6)
  - Maps - Germany, 1920-1939 (Folder 81: 7)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1946-1955. (Map-case Map case)
  French anti-Communist post-World War II posters and proclamations